nomadesk.com 2016-06-10

# Privacy Policy | Nomadesk

Nomadesk is developed by Nomadesk NV (Ltd.), with headquarters at Kortrijksesteenweg 204, B-9830, Sint-Martens-Latem, Belgium, company registration number BE-0867.499.902.

Thank you for visiting our web site nomadesk.com (the Site). This privacy policy tells you how we use personal information collected at this Site. Please read this privacy policy before using the site or submitting any personal information. By using the Site, you are accepting the practices described in this privacy policy. These practices may be changed, but any changes will be posted and changes will only apply to activities and information on a going forward, not retroactive basis. You are encouraged to review the privacy policy whenever you visit the Site to make sure that you understand how any personal information you provide will be used.  
Note: the privacy practices set forth in this privacy policy are for this web site only. If you link to other web sites, please review the privacy policies posted at those sites.

**Collection of Information:  
**We collect personally identifiable information, like names, postal addresses, email addresses, etc., when voluntarily submitted by our visitors. The information you provide is used to fulfill you specific request. This information is only used to fulfill your specific request, unless you give us permission to use it in another manner.

**Cookie and  Tracking Technology:  
**The Site uses cookie and tracking technology. Cookie and tracking technology are useful for gathering information such as browser type and operating system, tracking the number of visitors to the Site, and understanding how visitors use the Site. Cookies can also help customize the Site for visitors. Personal information cannot be collected via cookies and other tracking technology, however, if you previously provided personally identifiable information, cookies may be tied to such information. Aggregate cookie and tracking information may be shared with third parties.

**Distribution of Information:  
**We may share information with governmental agencies or other companies assisting us in fraud prevention or investigation. We may do so when: (1) permitted or required by law; or, (2) trying to protect against or prevent actual or potential fraud or unauthorized transactions; or, (3) investigating fraud which has already taken place. The information is not provided to these companies for marketing purposes.

**Commitment to Data Security:  
**Your personally identifiable information is kept secure. Only authorized employees, agents and contractors (who have agreed to keep information secure and confidential) have access to this information. All emails and newsletters from this Site allow you to opt out of further mailings.

**Privacy Contact Information:  
**If you have any questions, concerns, or comments about our privacy policy you may contact us using the information below:

  * By e-mail: privacy@nomadesk.com
  * By Phone: +32 9 233 68 86

We reserve the right to make changes to this policy. Any changes to this policy will be posted.

## Encrypted Local Drive

Nomadesk creates a secure area on your local hard drive called a Vault. All folders and files stored on a Vault are protected by 256-bit encryption. When the Nomadesk application is closed, your Vaults are invisible, making it impossible for unauthorized individuals to access your private data. Starting the Nomadesk application, and entering your personal password (only known by you) unhides the Vaults and makes them readily available within your standard file management applications (i.e., Windows Explorer, Mac Finder).  
Using SAML, the authentication can be done against your Active Directory.

## Theftguard Remote Track & Wipe

In the event your computer or mobile device is stolen, Nomadesk uses a unique serial number assigned to each device to give you the ability to remotely wipe all files and folders on your cached Nomadesk Vaults. The tracking even allows you to locate the missing device on Google Maps.

## Unlimited Storage

Hard drives crash and computers get stolen but that doesn’t mean you data will be lost. Every time a file is changed or a new file is saved on your Vault it gets backed up to the cloud. Since your files are backed up to redundant servers in the cloud, Nomadesk provides instant disaster recovery. The unlimited backup is subject to our Fair Usage Policy to ensure users are afforded equal access to the cloud.  
We maintain datacenter facilities in Europe and USA for our European and American customers, respectively.

## File Revisions / Backup

Data loss prevention is also available when your files are accidently deleted. Nomadesk retains backups of your Vaults allowing you to retrieve past version with a simple restore function from your Nomadesk online portal.

## Online Trashcan

When a file is deleted on a shared Vault, all individuals sharing the Vault have the file deleted from their local drive. In the event files are deleted when you didn't want them to be deleted, all files are preserved in your Online Trashcan.

## FileLink

Instead of e-mailing large files, FileLink allows you to e-mail a short-URL. The recipient clicks the link to download the file from your Vault in the Nomadesk cloud. A plugin for Outlook is available to generate FileLinks on the fly while writing the e-mail. Links can carry your corporate branding.

## FolderLink

FolderLink allows you to provide access to an entire folder of files on your secure server. Instead of initiating a file download (like a FileLink), FolderLink directs the recipient to a web page where they view and upload files (if given authority to do so). FolderLink is simple to use and can replace more complicated services like FTP. Links can carry your corporate branding.

## Get Link…

Right-click on any Nomadesk folder or file to create and copy a short-URL to the clipboard. Then paste the URL in emails, on Twitter, on Facebook, in documents, etc. Links can carry your corporate branding.

## Access Control

Exchanging files with individuals in your extended network emphasizes the need for additional security. FileLinks and FolderLinks therefore include the following options: password protected links, a limitation on the number of file downloads allowed, and expiration dates for when the links no longer function.

## File Download Tracking

Both FileLink and FolderLink allow you to receive an e-mail whenever the recipient downloads a file that has been shared.

## Website Widget

The Nomadesk "Embed in your site" option for folders allows you to create a widget for your web site or blog. The widget can be used to share the contents of any folder on your Vault. There is even an option allowing users to upload files to your folder.

## Automatic Sync

There is no need to worry about synchronizing your files and folders, simply drag and drop or save your documents directly to the Vault and Nomadesk does the rest. Every time you log on, Nomadesk scans the online Vault and automatically synchronizes the files that have been added or changed by other team members.

## Delta Sync

Nomadesk employs DeltaSync technology to speed up the synchronization process by only updating the portions of the file that have changed.

## File Access Settings

Sharing data in a Vault means you see the same files and folders on your local drive as all others sharing the same Vault, subject to the prevalent access settings. Each individual – accessing the Vault – may be given different rights to view/edit (therefore sync), invite others, send FileLinks or FolderLinks, etc.

## File Notifications

Keep track of when others add, delete, or modify files within your shared Vault. File Notifications allow you to set e-mail alerts on specific files or entire Vaults so you can keep track of any changes to your files.

## Ignore Files

Sometimes files are too sensitive to share but you want to keep them within your shared Vault for organization purposes. The ignore files action allows you to tag files within your local drive you do not wish to share with others. Ignore files can also be used to stop very large files from synchronizing until you have higher bandwidth connectivity.

## Online File Manager

The Nomadesk online dashboard gives you the ability to easily manage your files from any computer through a secure connection. You can use the intuitive file manager to view your Vaults, upload multiple files at once, move, copy and rename files, preview photos, and share files with FileLink.

## Windows Explorer / Mac Finder Integration

Your primary interface to files does not change, Nomadesk features are added into the right-click menu of Windows Explorer and Mac Finder.

## Mobile Apps

Nomadesk has mobile applications for iPhone, iPad, Windows Phone, Blackberry and Android devices.

## Email2Folder

Each Nomadesk Vault has a unique email address allowing you or your team to email files directly to your Vault. The files are saved in a folder and available for review and refiling.

## Sync All Of Your Computers

Synchronize your business and personal computers so you always have access to your files regardless of the computer you are using.

## WebDAV

Alternatively, Nomadesk supports the WebDAV protocol; to allow Nomadesk users to map Vaults as network drives on a Linux desktop, for instance.
